Guide to the William Ward Watkin Papers, 1903-1956 MS 352
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series III. Academic Career, 1914-1949; 10 linear inches.
  Arranged in four sub-series - General, Architecture Department, Curator of Athletics and Curator of Grounds. The General sub-series includes information that couldn't be placed into another category. This series includes material specifically related to Watkin's academic positions.
  - Subseries A: General
    - Committee on Air Raid and Civilian Defense, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Faculty Club, 1927 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Sabbatical, 1928-1929 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Salaries, 1930, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Social invitations, 1920, 1935, 1942, 1947, 1949, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Subseries B: Architecture Department
    - Archi-Arts Ball, 1922, 1934-1937, 1939, 1942, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Architectural Society Minutes
      - 1919-22 (Box 7, Folder 24)
      - 1934-42 (Box 7, Folder 25)
      - 1942-47 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Architectural Society Plays, 1917 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence
      - 1925, 1939, 1943, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 28)
      - Faculty and Prospective Faculty, 1914, 1919-1920, 1926, 1934, 1939, 1940, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 29)
      - Edgar Odell Lovett, 1918-1919, 1921, 1924, 1926-1930, 1932, 1937, 1939-1942, 1944, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Frederick W. Brown, 1925, 1934, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - James H. Chillman, Jr., 1917, 1919-1922, 1925, 1934, 1936, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Claude E. Hooten, 1926, 1934, 1937, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - William McVey, 1927, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Special Advisory Committee for Fine Arts School, University of Pennsylvania (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Student Designs
      - And Awards, 1919-1921 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - First and Second Year Student Designs (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Fourth Year Designs, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Fifth Year Designs and Thesis drawings, Traveling Fellowship Drawings, and Sixth Year Theses (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Thesis Designs
      - 1927-28 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - n.d. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - John C. Tidden, 1914-1915, 1918-1920 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Traveling Scholarship in Architecture, 1927-1928, 1951-1952 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Yearbook
      - 1927-1928 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - 1928 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Subseries C: Curator of Athletics
    - The R Book, 1924, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence
      - 1916-1927 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - John W. Heisman, 1924, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - John Coombs, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Subseries D: Curator of Grounds
    - Tony Martino, Groundsman, 1918, 1920, 1926, 1937, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence
      - Detroit Heating and Lighting Co., 1918-1919 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - 1920-1929, 1934-1935, 1939, 1942-1944 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Series IV: Addendum
  - Negatives of early Rice Institute construction photographs (Box 10)
  - Watkin baby brush and comb in presentation box (Box 11)